SIEW LA PAN



FULL STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACTS

Singapore



+65 93976263



siewlapang@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Mechanical design engineer turned fullstack developer, with years of education and experience in physical product design. Looking forward to using my newly acquired coding skills to build and design useful and user-centered digital solutions and products in the near future. Portfolio available at https://siewla.github.io/portfolio/.

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE

> GENERAL ASSEMBLY, SINGAPORE 2020

· 6 months intensive full stack web development coding bootcamp.

MASTER OF SCIENCE

UNIVERSITY TECHNOLOGY MALAYSIA, MALAYSIA 2016

· Mechanical Engineering

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

PURDUE UNIVERSITY, UNITED STATES 2013

· Mechanical Engineering

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- NodeJS
- o ExpressJS
- SQL PostgreSQL
- O NoSQL MongoDB
- o jQuery
- o HTML5
- o CSS

PROJECTS

BRAIN OUT - CARDS

Description: A gauntlet of card puzzles that involve interactions with cards. Players have to complete tasks like clicking on the highest valued card, or move a bunch of cards into a box, etc. There are currently 10 levels.

Stack: Built with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

IDEAGRAM

Description: This application acts as a visual discovery engine for finding ideas like countries, recipes, home and style inspiration, and many more.

Stack: A full Stack application with Express JS (Node JS) and Template Engine (EJS).

PINAPPS •

Description: This application serves to help its users organise and share the apps they commonly use.

Stack: A full Stack application using MERN (MongoDB, React, Express and Node) Stack.

SWEET ACCOUNTANT

Description: This application is a financial management app. This app also has charts and graphs which are extremely helpful in visualizing users' expenditure against users' income.

Stack: A full Stack application using NERDS (Node, Express, React, Database using SQL) stack.

WORK EXPERIENCE

RDD ME ENGINEER | NOV 2019 - PRESENT

D&K ENGINEERING, SINGAPORE

 Working on designing a portable medical device under SGInnovate's awarded project.

MECHANICAL DESIGN ENGINEER | SEP 2018 -OCT 2019

DATUMSTRUCT (S) PTE LTD, SINGAPORE

· Participated in SIMTech Robotic Training (Knowledge transfer of Robot Operating System) and in charged of NEA Innovation Grant Call (Integrated Automonous Hard Floor Scrubber with Security Survellience Capbilities) technical write-up and conceptual design.

SENIOR MECHANICAL DESIGN ENGINEER | AUG 2016 - SEP 2017

MAGNUM ESSENCE SDN BHD. MALAYSIA

 Solely in charged from concept generation, design development, tooling, manufacturing, production up to assembly line in with vendors in China of products to secure existing Pinpad devices from Ingenico, Verifone and many

MECHANICAL DESIGN ENGINEER | OCT 2013 -AUG 2016

DYSON, MALAYSIA

 Involved in design and improve the drives mechanism and mobility of Dyson's first autononous vacuum cleaner, Dyson 360 Eye Robot Vacuum.